2.2, Organizational Process Assets,
OPS.
These are the plans, processes,
policies, procedures and knowledge bases
specific to and used by the performing
organization.
These assets influence the management of
the project.
Organizational process assets include any
artifact, practice or knowledge from any
or all of the performing
organizations involved in the
project that can be used
to execute or the project.
The organizational process assets also
include the organization's lessons learned
from previous projects and historical
information.
Organizational process
assets may include completed
schedules, risk data
and earned value data.
That's from Pinball Guide page 39.
Please remember for the exam that the
organizational process assets include
lessons learned and historical data such
as schedule risk data and earned value
data from previous projects and that's it
very important because in most of the
processes throughout the project PIMs
suggested you check the lessons learned
and historical data and now you know where
to find it.
It's also important to remember for the
exam that lessons learned on previous
projects are held in the lessons learned
repository Lessons Learned on the current
project are held in the Lessons Learned
Register.
At the end of the project, the Lessons
Learned Register is edited and finalized
and then copied to the Lessons Learned
repository.
The next important point is all
organizational process assets are internal
to the organization and the
project team members may be
able to update them and add
to them throughout the project.
However, and please note this carefully,
it is usually only the knowledge basis and
not the processes, policies and procedures
that are changed.
I said usually there can be exceptions,
but usually it's not the processes,
policies and procedures that are changed
by the project team.
If you remember back to
enterprise environmental
factors, the project team can change them.
The enterprise environment defectors is
split into two categories, internal to the
organization and external to the
organization.
Now we come to the organizational
process assets we find they
are also split into two
categories, but both are internal.
Policies, processes and procedures and the
organizational databases.
As I mentioned before,
generally it is just the
knowledge basis that are
changed throughout the project.
For example, financial
performance information, lessons
learned, performance
metrics, issues and defects.
These are constantly updated throughout
the project.
Processes, policies and procedures are
usually established by the project
management office or by management and can
be updated only by following the
appropriate organisational policies and
processes.
Some organisations
encourage the team to tailor
templates, life cycles and
checklists for the project.
These artefacts can be
found in the organisational
knowledge basis within the
organisational process assets.
I'm just reading the following list from
the PIMBOC guide as they're quite simple
and don't really need any further
explanation.
Category 1, processes, policies and
procedures.
The organisation's
processes and procedures for
conducting project work
include initiating and planning.
Guidelines and criteria for tailoring the
organisation's set of standard processes
and procedures to satisfy the specific
needs of the organisation.
Specific organisational standards such as
policies, e.g.
human resource policies, health and safety
policies, secured income confidentiality
policies, quality policies, procurement
policies and environment policies.
product and project life cycles and
methods and procedures, e.g.
project management methods, estimation
metrics, process audits, improvement,
targets, checklists and
standardised process
definitions for use in the organisation.
Templates, for example, project management
plans, project documents, project
registers, report formats, contract
templates, risk categories, risk statement
templates, probability and impact
definitions, probability and impact
matrices and stakeholder register
templates and pre-approved supplier lists
and various types of contractual
agreements for example fixed price cost
reimbursable and time
and materials contracts
as we will cover in the
cost knowledge area.
Executing monitoring and controlling
change control procedures including the
steps by which performing organization
standards, policies, plans and procedures
or any document, any project
documents will be modified
and how any changes will
be approved and validated.
Traceability matrices, financial control
procedures, for example, shed reporting,
require expenditure and
disbursement reviews,
accounting codes and
standard contracting provisions.
Issuing defect management procedures,
for example, defining a and defect
controls, identify and resolving issues
and defects and tracking action items.
Resource availability control and
assignment management.
Organizational communication requirements,
for example, specific communications
technology available, authorised
communication media, record retention
policies, video conferencing, collaborative
tools and security requirements.
Procedures for prioritising approving and
issuing work.
in work authorizations,
templates, for example,
risk register, issue log and change log.
Standardised guidelines, work
instructions, proposed evaluation criteria
and performance measurement
and criteria and product
service or result verification
and validation procedures.
That brings the closing.
Project closure guidelines or
requirements, example, final project
audits, project evaluations, deliverable
acceptance, contract disclosure,
resource assignments and knowledge
transfer to production and or operations.
Category 2.
Organizational Knowledge Repositories The
organizational knowledge repositories for
storing and retrieving information include
the configuration management knowledge
repositories containing the versions of
software and hardware components and
baselines of all performing
organization standards,
policies, procedures and
any project documents.
Financial data repositories containing
information such as labour hours,
incurred costs, budgets and any project
cost overruns.
Historical information and lessons learn
knowledge repositories, e.g.
project records and documents,
or project closure information and
documentation, information regarding both
the results of previous project selection,
decisions and previous
project performance information
and information from
risk management activities.
Issue and defect management data
repositories contain issue and defect
status control information, issue and
defect resolution and action item results.
Data repositories for matrices used to
collect and make available measurements
data to processes and products and project
files in previous projects, for example
scope, cost, schedule and performance
measurement baselines, project calendars,
project schedule network diagrams, risk
registers, risk reports
and stakeholder registers.
And reminder, this is a list of what's
typically held in
organizational process assets.
And that brings us to the end of
Next lesson is 2.3 organizational systems.
Please read the corresponding chapter in
the PIMBOC guide
before watching the video.